Guide to the Judson Memorial Church Oral History Archive MSS.232
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: Oral History Interview Audio Discs, 2008
  - Subseries A: Audio - Access Copies, 2008
    - Arthur Levin Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/24/2008, ID: 232.0087 (Box Shared Fales 142, Cd 232.0087)
      Disc 2 of 2 (71 minutes total)
      Track 11: Military service experience
      Track 12: Late 1960s activism
      Track 13: AIDS task force
      Track 14: Prositution project
      Track 15: Late political involvement, disillusioned
      Track 16: Appreciation of Judson
      Track 17: Brainstorming youth programs, early
    - Mary Meyer Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/26/2008, ID: 232.0089 (Box Shared Fales 142, Cd 232.0089)
    - Mary Meyer Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/26/2008, ID: 232.0091 (Box Shared Fales 142, Cd 232.0091)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part One, Disc One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 10/15/2008, ID: 232.0093 (Box Shared Fales 142, Cd 232.0093)
      Howard Moody Oral History (Part 1)
      October 15, 2008
      Disc 1 of 2(77:37 minutes)
      Track 1: Childhood, early life
      Track 2: Santa Barbara (post-WWII)
      Track 3: Parents, family background
      Track 4: Seminary (Colgate Rochester/Yale)
      Track 5: Pacifism, early Judson experience
      Track 6: Ohio State years
      Track 7: Importance of urban culture/experience
      Track 8: Coming to Judson
      Track 9: Early experience at Judson, VID
      Track 10: Early Judson arts efforts, youth efforts
      Track 11: Exodus
      Track 12: Village Aid Service Center, drugs
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part One, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 10/15/2008, ID: 232.0095 (Box Shared Fales 142, Cd 232.0095)
      Disc 2 of 2 (50:46 minutes)
      Track 1: Theory on drug rehab
      Track 2: Al Carmine, Judson Players' Theatre
      Track 3: Dance, Poets Theatre
      Track 4: Publicity and growth
      Track 5: Clashes with the NYC and NYU
      Track 6: Runaway shelter, mobile clinic
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008, ID: 232.0097 (Box Shared Fales 142, Cd 232.0097)
      Howard Moody Oral History (Part 2)
      Disc 1 of 3 (176:47 minutes total)
      Track 1: Late 1960s, runaway projects
      Track 2: Runaway youth arts program
      Track 3: Politics and social change (1968)
      Track 4: Abortion Clinic
      Track 5: Clergy Consultation Service
      Track 6: Prostitution Project
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008, ID: 232.0099 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0099)
      Disc 2 of 3 (176:47 minutes total)
      Track 7: Prostitution Project/AIDS Task force
      Track 8: 1990, financial crisis
      Track 9: Welcoming Church, growth of Judson
      Track 10: Looking back from now, treatise
      Track 11: Civil Rights movement, involvement
      Track 12: Current (2008) gay issues, Prop 8
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Three, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008, ID: 232.0101 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0101)
      Disc 3 of 3 (176:47 minutes total)
      Track 13: 1968 Democratic Convention experience
      Track 14: Vietnam War -- protest movement
      Track 15: Physical Space of Judson
      Track 16: American exceptionalism
      Track 17: Worship service at Judson, changes
      Track 18: Censorship
      Track 19: Let things go...
      Track 20: Representative of Congregation
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008, ID: 232.0103 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0103)
      Judson Church Oral History Project: Maxine Phillips
      October 21, 2008
      Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi
      Disc 1 of 2 (1:53:47)
      Judson Church Oral History Project
      Track 1: Childhood in Pennsylvania
      Track 2: Parent's Background and History
      Track 3: Religious Background
      Track 4: Sense of Being the 'Other'
      Track 5: Academic Background
      Track 6: Study Abroad in France
      Track 7: Graduate School at Syracuse
      Track 8: Religious Involvement in College
      Track 9: Children's Religious Upbringing
      Track 10: Introduction to Judson Church
      Track 11: Runaway House at Judson
      Track 12: Organizing Welfare Rights at Judson
      Track 13: Communal Living in Brooklyn
      Track 14: Child Welfare League
      Track 15: Life Planning Project at Judson
      Track 16: Courtship and Wedding to Tom Roderick
      Track 17: 1980s - Motherhood and Career at Dissent
      Track 18: Reflections on Judson Church - Why Judson?
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008, ID: 232.0105 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0105)
      Disc 2 of 2 (1:53:47)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008, ID: 232.0107 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0107)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008, ID: 232.0109 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0109)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008, ID: 232.0111 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0111)
      Tom Roderick
      Part 1 of 3
      Interviewed by Adina Langer
      10/24/08
      wav file
      37:53
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008, ID: 232.0113 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0113)
      Tom Roderick Part 2 of 3 Interviewed by Adina Langer 10/24/08 wav file 42:09 Judson Church Oral History Project
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Three, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008, ID: 232.0115 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0115)
      Tom Roderick Part 3 of 3 Interviewed by Adina Langer 10/24/08 wav file 42:14 Judson Church Oral History Project
    - Tamara Rowe Oral History, Interviewed by Keara Duggan, 11/02/2008, ID: 232.0117 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0117)
      Tamara Oral History
      November 2, 2008
      Interviewed by Keara Duggan
      Disc 1 of 1 (56 min 50 sec)
      For NYU Oral History Course - Fall 2008
      Track 1: Introduction by Keara Duggan
      Track 2: Brooklyn Neighborhoods
      Track 3: Joining the Lafayette Avenue Presbyterian Church
      Track 4: Childhood in Bedford Stuyvesant and Food
      Track 5: Living in Fort Greene
      Track 6: Career as a Teacher
      Track 7: Teaching and Higher Education
    - Carolee Schneemann Oral History, Interviewed by Joanna Steinberg, 11/25/2008, ID: 232.0119 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0019)
      Carolee Schneeman Oral History
      11/25/2008
      Disc 1 (45 minutes)
      Track 1: Introduction to Judson Church; early uses of the body in art; "protofeminist" and "transgressive" movement in Judson Dance Theater; coherence and dissention in choreographic styles within the Judson group; emergence of art scene at Judson Church in 1960s
      Track 2: Continued emergence of art scene at Judson; meaning of church as a space for performance; relationship between artists and members of Judson Church; Schneemann's artistic process
      Track 3: Audience members and their responses; Newspaper Event; Meet Joy; Freedom of Expression at Judson Church; political implications of Judson aesthetic; relevant political issues and involvement (anti-Vietnam movement and feminism)
      Track 4: "Interior Scroll"; inclusion of women in art criticism; teaching positions and practices; overall impressions and reflections on experiences at Judson Church
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008, ID: 232.0121 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0121)
      Judson Oral History Project:
      Rachel Tenney and Bethnene Trexel
      November 19, 2008
      Disc 1 of 2 (1:27:5)
      Track 1: Childhood at Judson
      Track 2: Teenage Years at Judson
      Track 3: Youth Activities/Teaching Judson Beliefs
      Track 4: Past and Present Activism at Judson
      Track 5: Acceptance and Activism
      Track 6: Teaching Sunday School at Judson
      Track 7: Leaving Judson, Macalester College
      Track 8: Personal Growth/Changes at Judson
      Track 9: Bethnene's Description of Rachel's Childhood at Judson
      Track 10: Growth of Congregation
      Track 11: Rachel's Baptism at Judson
      Track 12: Bethnene's Reaction to Rachel's Rededication
      Track 13: Bethnene's Childhood/Religious Background
      Track 14: Bethnene's experience in NYC/Judson Church
      Track 15: Bethnene's Activism work during Rachel's Childhood
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008, ID: 232.0123 (Box Shared Fales 141, Cd 232.0123)
      Disc 2 of 2 (1:27:5)
  - Subseries B: Audio - Originals, 2008
    - Bebe Anderson Oral History, Interviewed by Ashley Welch, 12/9/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_35 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0001)
      General
    - Holly Bean Oral History, Interviewed by Elizabeth Banks, 11/18/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_2 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0002)
    - Reathel Bean Oral History, Interviewed by Kait Medley, 10/10/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_3 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0003)
    - Keen Berger Oral History, Interviewed by Elizabeth Banks, 10/10/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_4 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0004)
    - Malcolm Goldstein Oral History, Interviewed by Joanna Steinberg, 10/16/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_5 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0005)
    - Grace Goodman Oral History, Interviewed by Brigid Harmon, 10/16/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_6 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0006)
    - Peggy Halsey Oral History, Interviewed by Ashley Welch, 10/20/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_7 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0007)
    - Sue Harwig Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/17/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_8 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0008)
    - Sue Harwig Oral History Part Two, Interviewed Adina Langer, 10/17/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_9 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0009)
    - Sue Harwig Oral History Part Three, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/17/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_10 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0010)
    - Rose James Oral History Part One, 10/17/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_11 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0011)
    - Rose James Oral History Part Two, 11/10/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_12 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0012)
    - Harry Koutoukas Oral History, Interviewed by Kait Medley, 11/11/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_13 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0013)
    - Arthur Levin Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/24/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_14 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0014)
    - Arthur Levin Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/24/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_15 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0015)
    - Mary Meyer Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/26/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_16 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0016)
    - Mary Meyer Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/26/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_17 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0017)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part One, Disc One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 10/15/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_18 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0018)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part One, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 10/15/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_19 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0019)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc One, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_20 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0020)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Two, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_21 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0021)
    - Howard Moody Oral History Part Two, Disc Three, Interviewed by Stacey Satchell, 11/18/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_22 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0022)
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_23 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0023)
    - Maxine Phillips Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 10/21/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_24 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0024)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_25 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0025)
    - Anna Lou Pickett Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Breanne Scanlon, 10/19/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_26 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0026)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_27 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0027)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_28 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0028)
    - Tom Roderick Oral History Part Three, Interviewed by Adina Langer, 10/24/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_29 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0029)
    - Tamara Rowe Oral History, Interviewed by Keara Duggan, 11/02/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_30 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0030)
    - Carolee Schneemann Oral History, Interviewed by Joanna Steinberg, 11/25/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_31 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0031)
    - Steve Studnicka Oral History, Interviewed by Brigid Harmon, 12/02/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_32 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0032)
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part One, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_33 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0033)
    - Rachel Tenney and Bethene Trexel Oral History Part Two, Interviewed by Laura Zeccardi, 11/19/2008, FA_MSS_232_ER_34 (Box 3, Cd ID: 232.0034)
  - Audio CD Inserts, 2008; 1 folder (Box Shared Fales 115, Folder 6)
  - Subseries C: Audio - Submasters - CLOSED
    - ID 232.0046-232.0122 (Box Shared Fales PM 1)
- Series IV: 2010 Oral History Interviews, 32 Gigabytes in 1 flash drive
  This series is arranged alphabetically by interviewee surname.
  This series contains digital audio recordings of 11 oral histories conducted by Joanne Steinberg in 2010. Interviewees include: Yvonne Rainer, Steve Paxton, David Vaughan, Aileen Passloff, Elaine Summers, Margaret Wright, and other members of Judson Memorial Church.
  Historical Note
  As Joanna Steinberg was working on the Church exhibition curated at Fales Library around 2010, when she conducted additional oral histories with artists in the Judson Dance Theater (including Steve Paxton and Yvonne Rainer), as well as congregants who had been part of the Judson Poets Theater. These new interviews grew out of Steinberg's graduate studies when she had collected several oral histories in Rachel Bernstein's course which were included in the Judson Oral History Project. These interviews cover new ground, exploring the social context of the church, and recording the artists' reflections as they look back on their involvement at Judson 50 years later.
  - Reathel Bean, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_36
  - Grace Goodman, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_38
  - Lee Guilliatt and Essie Bordon, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_39
  - Craig Kuehl, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_40
  - Aileen Passloff, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_41
  - Steve Paxton, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_42
  - Yvonne Rainer, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_43
  - Elaine Summers, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_37
  - David Vaughn, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_44
  - Margaret Wright, 2010; FA_MSS_232_ER_1